# Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+64 27 387 9860 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

## **SUMMARY**

I'm an engineer with several years of experience developing native iOS games and applications both in academic and professional projects. I have experience developing REST APIs for communicating with clients and servers. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both by myself and in a team.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## iOS Developer, Barista Ventures

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — abr 2015 - current

I'm a member and leader of the iOS developer team, currently i'm in charge of 2 iOS app: PickUp (<a href="https://appsto.re/i6SD57B">https://appsto.re/i6SD57B</a>, and driver version), and i'm working on 2 more iOS apps for Startups, currently i'm working remotely from Australia.

### iOS Developer, Periferia IT

Bogotá, Cundinamarca, Colombia — apr 2014 - jun 2015

I was a member and leader of the iOS developer team, i was in charge of 3 iOS apps: weHive (<a href="http://www.wehive.co.uk">http://www.wehive.co.uk</a>), The Squawka Football App (<a href="https://appsto.re/i6B986K">https://appsto.re/i6B986K</a>) and a in-house app

# iOS Developer, Rokk3r Labs

Bogotá, Cundinamarca, Colombia — oct 2014 - may 2015

I was an outsourced iOS developer, i worked in 4 iOS apps for startups in the USA

#### iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — jun 2013 - apr 2014

I was a member of the iOS development team, I was in charge of several apps and participated in the development of more than 6 other apps

## iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts! Game (https://youtu.be/RfIVtL0y690), their free version and two other games that are not in the AppStore yet, GoBo( http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ\_NE ) and StreetRep ( http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM ); also i developed the ipad version of an app for a colombian retail firm named ÉXITO (https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9)

### iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed several frameworks for use in house and also started the development of several iOS games.

## iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed several iOS native apps for external clients, some of these applications are still live in the AppStore with the following links:

- <a href="https://itun.es/i6FV2yH">https://itun.es/i6FV2yH</a> (internet radio station, Medellin Hip Hop)
- <a href="https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3">https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3</a> (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia, Sushi Market)
- <a href="https://itun.es/i6Sn9c2">https://itun.es/i6Sn9c2</a> (app for a Marathon in Medellin-Colombia)
- events list for ANDI (app is not available in the AppStore)
- social network using GPS called MNU, this app is not currently in use.

#### **TUAPP Contest 2013**

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, we we're finalists with an application that suggests other ways of tourism using quests (http://www.seekit.info/).

## **EDUCATION**

# **EAFIT University** (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

# **SKILLS**

- Swift for iOS
- Objective-C and iOS development for iOS 4.3 and above
- Xcode.
- PHP.
- MySQL.
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments
- Cocos2D, Box2D and Unity frameworks for mobile game developing.
- Java.
- C#
- WCF for REST API
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, flash, premiere)